

London, E8 4JT bianchini.cecilia@gmail.com +44 7436 949815

Languages

Italian: Native

English: Postgraduate Degree

French: DELF B2

Profile

I'm a communication designer whose research revolves around visual products and their impact on society. My current practice ranges from web to branding production, with a particular interest in experimenting with AR and VR.

I recently graduated from Central Saint Martins, London, with a MA in Graphic Communication Design. Before moving to London I pursued a BA in Communication Design at Politecnico di Milano.

Education

University of the Arts London

Central Saint Martins October 2016 – June 2018 MA Graphic Communication Design

Politecnico di Milano, Italy

October 2012 – September 2015 BA Communication Design

École supérieure des arts Saint-Luc

Liége Belgium January 2015 - June 2015 Erasmus

Exhibitions

2018 Central Saint Martins Degree Show

Together with my coursemates we produced our Master final exhibition. I was part of the production team. Our task was to take decisions on the exhibition setup

2018 Feminist Library London

A documentary I made: 'Bravoh!' has been exhibited as part of the exhibition: 'Archiving the feminist experience'

2017 Barbican Curious Festival

A piece I worked on, along with other, has been exhibited at The Barbican as part of MAP making 2017 - London

2015 Engraving biennial of Liège

A series of engravings about tarantism I produced have been exhibited at Engraving Biennial of Liège 2015

2015 DESIGN X DESIGNERS

My reportage 'On board of the Adriatic. A night of fishing' has been selected to be exhibited at the Design Week, Politecnico di Milano

2014 "Moleskinabile" Exhibition

Contest promoted by Moleskine, where we've been asked to sketch frames of the Salone del Mobile, Milano Design Week.

My moleskine has been selected to be exhibited.

2011 Amref contest exhibition in Latina

A poster I made called H2NO has been exhibited in Latina, Rome, as part of the final selection for the contest Amref - Africa

Work experience

Freelance Graphic Web Designer London

April 2019 - ongoing

I'm currently freelancing in London as a graphic and interaction designer for agencies such us: Monokoto, FLUUUID Plait Creative and Era Studio Berlin; producing for them bespoken brand identitied and digital contents.

Digital Graphic Designer

Parcodiyellowstone, Milan

October 2018 - March 2019

Parcodiyellowstone is a brand, digital agency based in Milan. I worked for them in a team of 5 people. Under the supervision of the two creative directors, I designed brand identities and digital applications. Together with them, I took part in meetings and dealt with the clients' requirements.

- Digital design: Website concept and wireframe / website layout / website coding (assistent)
- Editorial production: publications

Visual Artist

Otolab, Milan

October 2018 - March 2019

Otolab is a Milan based collective of artists, web designers, vjs and videomakers.

Meeting once a week, we experimented with electronic music and visual researches, to create compelling immersive experiences.

AR/VR Visual Designer

1RIC studio, Los Angeles

July - August 2018

I collaborated with the studio in the production of their next AR movie. The clip is shot with depth capture and designed for Microsoft Magic Leap. I worked in a team of 3 people as a visual designer. The coding part was meanly coordinated by an Unity engineer, but I do have some knowledge on c#. The project was sponsored by RYOT and it featured at Sundance Film Festival in January 2019

Freelance Graphic Designer

Plait Creative, London

August 2017 - June 2018

Plait Creative is a brand digital agency based in London, I worked in the studio 2/3 days per week alongside my MA program. Together with the creative director, we designed and delivered graphics and brand identities.

- Brand Identity design:
 Competitors research / logo / mood board / applications / website
- Reports and presentations design: infographics + publications

Waitress - Bartender

The driver, London

October 2016 - May 2017

Farm worker

Seed solution, Pukekohe, New Zealand **February 2016 - March 2016**

I went to New Zealand on a working holiday. While there, I worked in a corn farm and travelled for three months, whilst earning my passage back to Italy, passing thruogh South East Asia.

Production and Backstage Assistaxnt

Master of Magic for Mediaset, Rimini **July 2015**

uly 2015

I helped in the backstage of this one-week wizard championship. The show has been recorded and broadcasted by Mediaset

- Artists welcoming
- Reception

Giancarlo Iliprandi Assistant

Triennale Design Museum, Milan

June 2013

I worked as assistant of the designer Giancarlo Iliprandi for the setting up of the exhibition:

'Triennale di Milano, 80 anni'

- · Calls, buying materials
- · Hand work for setting up

Volunteer experience

Volunteer

L'Africa Chiama, Soweto (slum of Nairobi, Kenya)

September 2014

I was helping dealing with and managing the N.G.O. activities.

- Maths / English class for street children
- Support for HIV mothers
- Assistant during the sessions of physiotherapy for disable people
- Assistant for managing the 'food project'

Scout group chef

A.G.E.S.C.I., Pesaro

October 2001 - August 2013

I've been part of a scout group since I was 8. For the last 3 years I joined the leaders group working with children and teenagers.

Planning / managing Summer Camps.
 Usually 12 days in the wood / mountains